We'll be right back.
I'm just so thankful for each and every one of you.
Our church really is a special place to be, and it's not because of the building we meet
in.
It's not because of anything other than the people that have built the culture around our
idea of what Jesus has called us to as a church.
And so I'm thankful for all of you.
This morning, we're wrapping up a little two-week series that we started last week, just on kind
of the vision for our church in 2026.
And last week, I introduced this idea that I really want 2026 to be a time where those
of us who would consider ourselves followers of Jesus, that we would take steps towards
maturity in our faith.
Two years ago, or in 2025, we had this focus of being a church that is welcome to those
who aren't yet following Jesus.
And what did it look like for us to make room for people who are struggling with, wrestling
with their faith and pursuing faith in Jesus?
And I want to hold those two things in tension because I always want to be a church where people
who are outside of the faith can come and can explore faith and can ask hard questions.
But at the same time, we as a church can lose our witness to the world if we actually aren't
obeying the principles of God's kingdom.
If we're gathering together as believers under the name of Jesus and we don't look anything
like Jesus, then our witness to the watching world diminishes.
And so if we're going to be a church that has influence, has kingdom impact in the world,
we have to actually understand what maturity looks like in the kingdom.
And so today, I really want to get more practical on what I think maturing faith looks like in
the kingdom of God, especially for those of us who are embracing King Jesus in our Western
culture in 2026.
Sound like a plan?
All right, I'm a little more congested than normal, so I'm going to try and fight through
that and you guys just work with me.
Sound good?
I asked you that twice, didn't I?
Just pray.
Let's pray.
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
We are grateful for another opportunity to gather together with the saints to cast our
mind on you, the lamb who was slain, who is sitting at the right hand of the Father, ruling
and reigning.
God, it is not just those of us gathered in this room, but there are hundreds of millions
of people gathered all around the world seeking to cast their eye on you, the ruler and reiner
of all creation.
God, that is going to become totally apparent to everyone one day, but until that day comes,
may we be a manifestation of what it looks like for you to rule and reign in our lives as
individuals and a community.
God, so much of our culture is individualized and the kingdom is not an individual thing that
we embrace.
It is a family that we join.
May we be a family who is committed to your kingdom values for your glory, for our good,
and for the good of our neighbors.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Put a few words on the screen here and let me know if you see anything that connects these
words.
Old news, bittersweet, jumbo shrimp.
That's the heartiest amen I've gotten from my father while preaching a sermon.
Freezer burn, deafening silence, unbiased opinion.
Anybody see?
We've got some oxymorons in the room.
Apparent contradictions, terms that we use together, but upon further investigation are at odds with
one another.
They're phrases that are so normal to our vocabulary and our vernacular that we don't even realize
or think about the fact that they contradict one another.
And this is a common human experience to not notice contradictions that are familiar to
us.
It's a common occurrence from my perspective, pastorally, for many Christians when it comes
to the way that we apply the kingdom of God.
Later in our text, we're actually going to see a Greek word for foolishness, and it's actually
where we get the word moron, right?
It's like there can be this way that we embrace the kingdom, but we embrace it in a contradictory
way.
We embrace a kingdom of God in a culture of this world, and we blend the two things.
And it's a common experience, and honestly, it's impossible to avoid.
Every individual person receives the message of the gospel in a particular culture, whether
you're here in America in 2026 or our brothers and sisters in house churches in China, they
all receive the gospel within a cultural context.
Every church exists within a particular culture, and if we are not careful, it will be really
easy for us to embrace the message of Jesus without seeing the ways the values of Jesus
contradict the values of our larger cultural context.
We can become walking oxymorons, and oftentimes we don't even realize we're doing it because
the culture that we live in is the water that we swim in.
It is the air that we breathe.
And so we don't even realize in some ways the way that the values of the kingdom of God come
in opposition to the values of our culture of the day.
I love how N.T. Wright puts it.
He says,
Christians often simply reflect the values and behaviors of their surrounding culture.
As any experienced missionary will confirm, when a tribe or ethnic group becomes Christian,
the people rarely get the whole package at once.
More often than not, Christianity simply becomes an add-on to their existing worldview.
This can result in a confused semi-Christian worldview, or in the worst cases, syncretism,
where we just use Christian language to talk about just our cultural values.
He says it can take years or even a generation for their faith to transform.
And this has been my personal experience.
I received the gospel of Jesus in an American context, and it's taken me 15 years to begin
to see some areas and some ways in which the gospel of Jesus actually confronts my American
culture.
And I think maturity in the kingdom of God is realizing where the values of the kingdom
of God and the values of the culture that we live in come in opposition to one another.
And if we are truly embracing Jesus as king, saying these values that my culture builds up,
these values that my culture says that I need to champion and chase,
I'm actually going to lay them aside for the values of the kingdom of God, the crucified Savior
who saved me and who has given me abundant and everlasting life.
I'm actually going to go with what he says.
And so maturity looks like us shedding some of our values that, and not all Western values
come up against the kingdom of God, right?
Like there's some beautiful things in our culture that reflect God's image and God's value.
There are beautiful things in our culture that people who don't embrace Jesus actually embrace,
and whether they call it Jesus values or not, they are Jesus values.
And so it's not that everything about being American is anti-Christian.
It's that we, as maturing followers of Jesus, we have to be able to distinguish where kingdom
values come in opposition to worldly values.
And this is the problem that we see in the church at Corinth.
We're going to open our Bibles to 1 Corinthians chapter 1 here in just a second.
And this is the problem that the Corinth church embraced.
They are a three- to five-year-old church who embraced the values of the kingdom of God,
but did not let the values of the kingdom of God challenge their cultural values.
They were embracing a kingdom gospel in a Corinthian way.
And I think these problems map really well onto the church in America today, individual churches
and the church as a whole.
We've embraced the gospel of Jesus in many ways in an American way more than a kingdom way.
Corinth was a port city with a very diverse group of people living there, lots of money,
but the money was shared by a small class at the top of the social ladder.
They were obsessed with Greek philosophy and wisdom.
It was a high value of the Corinthian culture.
Morality was not.
Most people living in Corinth had a deep desire to climb the social or economic ladder, no matter
the cost.
Does that sound familiar at all?
Nothing new under the sun.
The Corinthian problem is the American problem.
Our modern Western culture isn't much different.
Our cultural values are built on success.
We want to look like we're successful.
We want to achieve success doing whatever we can to climb the social or economic ladder.
See, the primary issue with this is Christ's definition of his kingdom people in Matthew chapter
five.
Let's read it really quick just to set the stage.
Matthew chapter five, starting in verse three, Jesus, when he's defining what the people of
his kingdom look like, he said, blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom
of heaven.
Blessed are those who mourn, for they will be comforted.
Blessed are the meek, for they will inherit the earth.
Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they will be filled.
Blessed are the merciful, for they will be shown mercy.
Blessed are the pure in heart, for they will see God.
Blessed are the peacemakers, for they will be called children of God.
Blessed are those who are persecuted because of righteousness, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Blessed are you when people insult you, persecute you, and falsely say all kinds of evil against
you because of my name.
Rejoice and be glad, because great is your reward in heaven.
For in the same way, they persecuted the prophets who were before you.
Many of us in the room, we'd read these red letters and we'd give a hearty yes and amen,
but if we look at the direction of our lives, we're obsessed with them looking nothing like this.
I love how one pastor puts it.
He says, the Corinthian church was allowing their culture and worldview to dominate the
way they interacted with the gospel.
And often I think that this is the maturity issue in the American church, that we're allowing
our Western culture to dominate the way that we receive and interact with the gospel rather
than the other way around.
Jesus doesn't say, my kingdom people are the powerful, successful, influential ones, the
ones good at climbing the social ladder, the ones good at winning cultural status, the ones
who retire at 55 and buy the beach property, the ones whose kids get sports scholarships.
It's not what he says.
He says, blessed are the meek, blessed are the poor in spirit.
This is a challenge to us, right?
It's the water we swim in.
Our culture is just, it is what it is.
It's where we exist and we have to see, we have to have eyes to see where the kingdom of
God comes in contradiction with the kingdom of this world.
Paul's challenge for the Corinthian church and ultimately for us is that we identify where
the values of the kingdom of God contradict the values of our culture.
And like I said, it's not all of them.
It's not like every value that our culture has is bad.
There's a lot of good values, but we have to identify where the values of our culture
come against the values of the kingdom of God.
We've got to examine our lives to see where we are embracing a semi-Christian worldview,
where we've blended the culture of this world with the culture of the kingdom of God.
All of us do it.
This message is extremely challenging for me because I've been a follower of Jesus for 20
plus years and I've seen all over my life a blending, a semi-Christian worldview.
I'm so American in so many ways and that's not all bad, but in some ways it comes in contradiction
to the kingdom.
And if I don't examine my life and allow King Jesus to confront some of my values that are
actually in opposition to his kingdom, then I will always kind of live this oxymoronic
life.
And if we are going to be a counter witness to the world around us, we can't be this hypocritical
semi-Christian life.
We have to be all in and that takes time, but we've got to be committed to it.
So we've got to identify, examine, and then ultimately redefine what our values are based
on the kingdom of God, even when they come against our broader culture.
That's what I want to do with the rest of our time, spend time identifying some of the values
that are in opposition, examining our lives for where we might be embracing the semi-Christian
worldview and then redefine our values based on God's kingdom.
Sound like a good roadmap for the rest of our time?
All right, good.
Let's do it.
First Corinthians chapter one, verse 18, Paul says, for the message of the cross is foolishness
to those who are perishing, but to us who are being saved, it is the power of God.
Skip down to verse 22.
He says, Jews demand signs and Greeks look for wisdom, but we preach Christ crucified, a stumbling
block to the Jews and foolishness to the Gentiles.
But to those whom God has called both Jews and Greek, Christ is the power of God and the wisdom
of God.
The church in Corinth was a blend of religious Jews and secular Gentiles, but both groups had
been heavily influenced by their Corinthian values of climbing the social or economic ladder.
The first critique Paul has is he says, Jews demand signs.
And we see this all over the religious people's interactions with Jesus.
They're constantly asking Jesus to do more.
Dance for us, Jesus, is the phrase that I would put in the mouth of the Pharisees.
They constantly want to see him prove himself with miraculous signs and with power.
The religious Jews expected God to show up and overthrow Rome.
They wanted a Messiah in the image of the world around them, one who would dominate their enemies
with strength and immediately thrust them as religious people into a position of power and influence.
And many of us with religious backgrounds and a culture obsessed with success still have this
perspective today.
We demand signs of God.
We have this underlying assumption that following Jesus will result in us having a successful and
influential life.
We expect God to answer our prayers because we are the faithful ones.
We expect for him to show up and do miraculous signs in our life so that his name will be glorified.
But my question is, what is our ultimate motivation?
Is it so that his name will be glorified?
Or is it so that we can climb the social and economic ladder of success?
We expect that our churches are going to be influential and powerful in our culture because
success in our culture looks like power and influence.
And when faith, listen to this, when faithfulness to Jesus doesn't lead to influence and power,
we cut corners in order to produce success for ourselves.
And the thing about the kingdom of God is Jesus never promises that we will have earthly
success and influence.
He actually says that you're going to be persecuted for my name.
And so we come with these cultural values of success and influence and we say, we're following
Jesus.
We're faithful to Jesus.
That means we're going to have influence.
We're going to be successful.
And I'm just not so sure that that happens that way.
And then we look, I just, I see it all over these churches that like build their churches
based on effective business principles.
Market, they bring in marketing firms.
I'm just like, man, I don't know.
I don't know that that's the kingdom of God as much as it is the semi-Christian worldview
where we're taking the gospel of Jesus in our culture and trying to produce success, trying
to climb up the social and economic ladder.
And I just think, I want to remind us that maturity means faithfulness to Jesus at all
costs.
And we've got to get comfortable with being at the bottom of the ladder if that's what
it takes to be faithful to Jesus.
And I'm not saying that faithfulness to Jesus doesn't mean that sometimes we'll have some
earthly success.
That's not what I'm saying.
But we've just got to get, we've got to identify where the values of the culture of our day come
against the values of the kingdom of God.
Earthly success, influence, and power was never a promised outcome of the gospel of the kingdom.
And it reflects more on the values of our culture than the values of the kingdom.
We need to take a step back and identify the values, where the values of our culture
have impacted or even dominated the way that we receive the message of Jesus.
The Jews, the religious, they looked for signs.
They wanted power.
They wanted God to show up and conquer their enemies now, today.
And if you don't do it my way, on my terms, then I'm not following you.
It says the Greeks looked for wisdom.
It's interesting here.
Paul rarely uses this term Greek.
He typically uses Gentile.
But I think he uses the word Greek intentionally to focus on the fact that the Corinthians were
obsessed with Greek philosophy.
This was their cultural value was we actually achieved this level of enlightenment and spiritual
like awakening based on our Greek philosophy.
The more that we know, the more enlightened that we become.
And it was this way of climbing up this ladder of success.
So he doesn't use the word Gentile.
He uses the word Greek to confront their culture and infatuated with Greek philosophy.
Many Gentiles in the Corinthian church had accepted the message, but were treating it like some
secular philosophy that made them more enlightened, that allowed them to climb up some social ladder,
and they held it with arrogance.
It was another status game inherited from their culture and not from the gospel of Jesus.
And again, many of us, myself included, often still do something resembling this today.
We embrace the wisdom of the Scriptures and blend it with the wisdom of our culture to create
a semi-Christian worldview that allows us to look down on others as less enlightened and
spiritual than we are.
And both groups were allowing their cultural values to dominate the way that they interact
with the gospel message.
And Paul's first desire for them is that they would identify it.
He's just calling it out.
Like, look around the culture.
The religious Jews in your culture and the secular Greeks in your culture, they both want
power and influence.
They want wisdom and power.
But we preach Christ crucified.
A message that looks foolish to those who are obsessed with power.
A stumbling block to those who are obsessed with power.
And it looks foolish to those who are obsessed with wisdom.
So first, we've got to identify.
And second, we have to examine.
We've got to examine where our culture comes in contradiction with the culture of Jesus.
In verse 22, Jews demand signs.
Greek looks for wisdom.
But we preach Christ crucified, a stumbling block to the Jews, foolishness to the Gentiles.
But to those whom God has called, both Jews and Greeks, all are welcome at the table of Jesus.
It's not divided on ethnic boundaries.
All are welcome to the kingdom.
But in order to come to the kingdom, you have to see that Christ is the power of God and the wisdom of God.
Paul's rebuke of the Corinthians is focused on Christ crucified.
And I want to point out here that this is not the only angle that you can take when preaching the gospel.
We often talk about the cross a lot when we talk about the gospel, but there are plenty of other angles that you could use when talking about the gospel.
The empty tomb of the resurrection, the ascension to the right hand of the Father.
There are some victorious, powerful images of the gospel that Paul could have used here.
But he chooses to use the most shameful, the most weak image of the gospel of Jesus.
Because these people need to be rebuked about their obsession with winning.
Their obsession with power and influence.
And he's doing something very pastoral here.
He's telling the church what they need to hear, even though it's hard.
I love, Mursa and I spent some time last year studying the book of Revelation.
And there's seven letters to the seven churches.
And each one has kind of different challenges and encouragements and rebukes.
There's actually two churches in the letters in Revelation that don't receive any rebuke from the apostle John.
And what's interesting to me is you study the two churches that don't receive any rebuke.
My assumption is not that they are a perfect church because we know that those do not exist.
But both of those churches were experiencing heavy persecution.
They were being persecuted for being Christians.
And so the apostle John doesn't come alongside these people who are beaten down and broken and dying for their faith and say, you need to clean yourself up.
He just encourages the heck out of them.
He reminds them that Jesus was raised, that Jesus ascended.
He reminds them that Jesus is sitting on the throne and they don't need to be afraid.
He encourages those who are discouraged.
But to a culture that has blended their culture of success and worldly power, he says, you need to focus on Christ crucified.
The image of Christ crucified is the exact opposite of the cultural values of Corinth and the exact opposite of our values of Western culture today.
Crucifixion was shameful for both Jews and Gentiles.
I wouldn't talk about it in polite society.
It was a symbol that would represent the opposite of their cultural values, weakness and foolishness.
But Paul says in the upside down kingdom, Christ crucified is actually the source of true power and true wisdom.
And so he's confronting them.
He's saying, examine what you're doing.
Examine the message that you've received versus the way that you've received it.
You've received a message of a Messiah who was crucified, shamefully.
This is the message you've received and you've received it in such a way where you're using it to try and climb the economic and social ladder of status and power and success.
Let's examine how these two things might be contradictory to one another.
It says the Christ crucified is the power of God.
Sacrificial love of enemy is actually where true power is found.
It looks like losing, but in the end, it leads to life.
Jesus says in his famous sermon on the mountain, he says,
It looks like foolishness to the world around us.
Our world tells us that if somebody comes against you, you come against them harder.
If somebody gossips about you, you slander about them.
If somebody does something to you, you do something to them because it's all about a game where we have to push others down to get higher up the ladder.
And Paul says the power of God is found on Jesus Christ crucified.
Sacrificial love of not just your neighbor, but also your enemy.
Culture says that if someone threatens your safety, you fight back and you win at all costs.
The kingdom says lay down your life for your enemy and trust in the abundant God who owns the cattle on a thousand hills.
He has everything in his hand.
If we believe that he is ruling and reigning, then we do not have to achieve success on our own.
We do not have to cut corners in kingdom faithfulness in order to produce our own success or victory.
We can trust him.
We can love our enemy.
It sounds crazy to those of us steeped in American culture, but I will just ask us one question this morning.
Actually, I'm going to end up asking you a lot of questions.
I don't know why I always put that in my notes.
I have one question right now in this moment for you.
And that is how well is our cultural value really working?
How well is this rat race to climb the ladder of social economic power and influence really working for us?
Individuals are running this rat race of success until everyone is run into the ground.
Exhausted, anxious, disappointed.
No one really wins.
Our nation is building more and more weapons and engaging in more and more wars around the world.
Is that actually leading us to the peace and safety that we are longing for?
The power of God.
Is people who embrace the value of the kingdom of God actually living the values of the kingdom of God?
And the beautiful thing about living in a culture that has some countercultural values to the kingdom is that when we are faithful to kingdom values, it's more obvious and apparent.
It becomes the light of the world.
It becomes the salt of the earth.
But only if we release our cultural values and embrace the values of the kingdom.
He says, not only is Christ crucified, the power of God, it is the wisdom of God.
This spiritual feeling of enlightenment that the Corinthians were longing for.
This internal sense of they have a relationship with the divine that they were longing for.
It's found in the person who is hanging on the cross.
The love and affirmation that you and I are looking for is found in the person on the cross.
When we were his enemies, Christ died for us.
This is the wisdom of God.
The creator of the universe loves you because you were created in his image.
You do not have to do anything to earn it.
You simply need to receive it on the cross.
The thing that the Corinthians were looking for, this enlightenment, this spiritual power that they were looking for, is actually found in Jesus who loved them even when they were his enemies.
This is the wisdom of God.
The thing I love about this is the Jews and the Greeks, they had the right instincts.
The Corinthian believers, they were looking for the right things.
They wanted to see God's power.
They wanted to know God's wisdom.
Baked within this searching is a desire for God.
They were just looking for it in the wrong places.
They think his power is like strength against their enemies and his wisdom is insight used to improve their earthly status.
But Christ crucified shows us that God's power over his enemies is demonstrated through his sacrificial love.
That his wisdom isn't used to elevate his own status, but to elevate the status of those beneath him.
And this is the message that we've been invited to embrace.
It's actually the example that he's called us to follow.
And we like to embrace the message without following the example.
Me, first and foremost, in that category.
I love how F.B. Meyer puts it.
Such a cool name.
You know, when somebody quotes me like 150 years from now, if one of my sermons ever lives on and somebody quotes me,
and they're like, as Ryan Miller once said.
I'm like, that doesn't sound cool.
F.B. Meyer.
As F.B. Meyer once said, he says,
This is the value of the kingdom of God coming against the value of this world.
That God has actually found as we stoop lower and surrender more.
So we identify the ways in which our idea of wisdom and power come against the ideas of the kingdom.
We examine how this impacts the way that we live our lives.
And ultimately, he wants us to redefine, build our lives on the true values of the kingdom of God.
But to those whom God has called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ is the power of God and the wisdom of God.
The question then becomes for us, do our lives, do our lived values align with the values of the kingdom of God?
Do our lived values, not our intellectually agreed upon values, but do the values that our lives are built on,
do they align with the values of the kingdom of God?
Or are we allowing our cultural values to dominate the way we have received and interacted with the gospel?
This is maturity in the kingdom.
Laying down the values of our culture and picking up the values of the kingdom of God.
Even when it looks like foolishness and weakness, it is the power and wisdom of God.
Is the ultimate aim of your life to achieve success by climbing the ladder with influence and wisdom?
Or are we content to trust Christ and meet him at the bottom of the ladder,
trusting that in him we will find abundant and everlasting life?
What is driving our life?
Are we trying to just keep getting a little bit higher, achieve a little bit more success,
do a little bit better than our neighbors are doing?
Or are we using our resources and our time and our energy to point to Christ crucified,
the power and wisdom of God?
That, I think, in some ways is an easier question to answer than the one I'm going to ask next.
And that is, for those of you that have children, this is where I think it really,
we've really got to work hard to define what it is that we're actually building our lives on,
the values that are actually important to us.
Because it's one thing to ask you,
are you trying to climb the social economic ladder with power and influence and success?
Or are you really trusting in Christ crucified?
It's another thing to ask, what cultural values are you imparting on your kids?
Are we trying to help our kids climb to the top of the social ladder through cultural power and influence?
Are we inviting them to see the beauty of Jesus at the bottom of the worldly ladder?
Are we setting them up for abundant and everlasting life?
Or are we leading them down a path of the anxious generation?
I would just go back to, is it working?
Is the way that secular American culture is raising children, is it working?
And if it's not working, and if we as objective people can stand back and say, it's not working,
then why is it that we are parenting our children in the exact same way that all of our neighbors are?
Why is it that we are, without words, telling our children that what success looks like
is climbing the ladder of social power and influence is succeeding?
It's not that success is bad.
I'm not saying that.
But what I'm saying is if we build their lives around achieving worldly success,
then what we're inviting them into is to spend their life running a treadmill that's going nowhere.
And maybe I'm just, maybe you guys are suffering the realities of having a pastor who has a two-year-old.
I'm thinking about these things now.
What do I want to give my child?
What values do I want him to see as important in life?
Books and books and books have been written about how anxious our kids are,
about how overwhelmed our kids are.
And what we need to give them is presence and sacrificial love, not a packed schedule.
Amen.
Paul's challenge to us, for those who are playing by the values of our culture,
Christ crucified is the rebuke we need.
Christ crucified is where power and wisdom are actually found.
But what I want to do this morning is go a little bit off of Paul's script
because I know that in a room this big, not all of us are dealing with this enmeshing of Western culture and kingdom culture.
Many of us are actually beaten down by the world.
We're tired.
We're sick.
We're suffering.
And the good news that we need to hear, the element of the gospel, the angle of the gospel that you need to hear this morning is not Christ crucified,
but Christ raised and Christ ascended and Christ seated on the throne, ruling and reigning and Christ returning to make all things new.
Some of us need to hear that your suffering is temporary, that it will not last.
Some of you need to hear what Paul says in Romans chapter eight,
that what we suffer now is nothing compared to the glory that he will reveal to us later.
So some of us need to be challenged with Christ crucified and some of us need to be encouraged with Christ raised,
Christ ascended and Christ returning.
So I don't know where you're at this morning.
I don't know what you're dealing with, but I know that the message of the gospel,
the power of God for salvation to everyone who believes.
It's the power for those of us who are clinging on to earthly success,
who are still trying to be influential and climb the ladder in our own merit.
The power of God is for us to be corrected and to meet Jesus at the bottom.
He says, are you tired, heavy laden?
Has the rat race of climbing the ladder left you exhausted, frustrated?
Take my yoke upon you, for my burden is easy.
For those of us that have just, we've been at the bottom.
We get, we just feel like we keep getting stepped on and kicked down.
Christ went to the cross to demonstrate one of the primary values of the kingdom of God.
But as he did that, he actually achieved ultimate victory and success over the final enemy of death and the grave.
Where, oh death, is your power?
Where, oh death, is your sting?
Praise be to God that Jesus is raised.
So I don't know where you're at.
I know that this was a heavy message for me personally, who just is a walking oxymoron.
I'll just tell you, I just am.
It's heavy, but it's encouraging.
Because it's actually the thing that we're looking for, power and wisdom is actually available to us.
We've just been looking in the wrong places.
So, this morning I pray that both Christ crucified and Christ raised will help us identify where our values and the values of the kingdom are in contradiction with one another.
We just take some time this week to examine our lives, to think about our schedules, our time, our money, how we invest the things that God's given to us.
How do they align with God's values and God's kingdom, and how do they align with the values of our culture?
And what might be some small changes or decisions that we might be invited by the Holy Spirit to make, to redefine the values of our lives based on the values of God's kingdom?
Let's pray.
Father in heaven, just thank you for another day, another opportunity to come into this place, this sanctuary, this old fire bingo hall.
And the thing that makes it sacred is not the space, but the people.
God, I thank you for the opportunity to remind ourselves that we are not in this alone, that we are a family of God.
That you're not inviting us as one individual out by ourself to go swim in the opposite current of the culture around us.
You're actually inviting all of us as a group to swim in the opposite current together.
God, give us power and strength and wisdom in the community to live your values.
To be aware of where the values of this world have blended with a message of the gospel that we've received.
God, challenge us, convict us.
And for those of us that are just so discouraged already, God, remind us of the hope of the resurrection.
That this suffering will not last.
That it is light and temporary compared to the glory that will be revealed to us in Jesus.
I pray all of this in Jesus' name.
Amen.
I think we forgot to announce communion.
We were actually going to do the tables and stuff, but it didn't work out this morning.
So we have pre-made cups.
If you didn't get a chance to get them, you can go grab, uh, are there any left?
We're out.
We're out of Christ's body broken for you and his blood shed for you.
That's disappointing.
We got two extras.
We got two.
I got one.
It's what happens when you're, nevermind.
We got sick.
We got sick today.
Our plans got a little off.
So let's pray for multiplication of the bread and the juice.
There I am demanding signs again, you know?
All right.
So what's interesting to me is Jesus gives us this regular reminder of Christ crucified.
His body broken and his blood shed.
It's, it's, it's almost meant to come in opposition to our cultural values on a regular basis.
It's almost meant to let us look at Christ's body broken, his blood shed on a regular basis because he knows that we are prone to forget.
That the message of the cross looks like weakness and foolishness to the world around us.
And this is what the Corinthians were doing.
They were actually so influenced by their cultural values that even when they were taking his body and his blood, the image of Christ crucified,
they were doing it in a way that promoted power, wealth, and status.
The rich were getting there early and getting drunk and eating all of the bread until it was gone.
And those slaves and working people who had to work all day got there and there was nothing left.
And all they saw was their brothers and sisters having a drunken party.
Talk about taking the image of kingdom values and allowing your cultural values to dominate the way that you take it.
And I just want to say this is why we try and take communion as often as possible as a church.
Because we need to be reminded of Christ crucified, his body broken for us, his blood shed for us.
Because we are all so prone to wander.
Lord, I feel it.
It's a reminder of enemy love, of sacrificial service.
It's a reminder that Jesus invites us to meet him at the bottom of the ladder.
So may this morning, this opportunity be for us to realign our lives with the values of God's kingdom seen clearly through Christ crucified.
The power and wisdom of God.
Let's take Christ's body broken for you.
Let's drink Christ's blood shed for you.
Church, I'm thankful for a congregation of people that allow me to challenge myself in front of you in a way that is hard.
May we be a people that are continually being conformed into the image of the kingdom of God on earth as it is in heaven.
Father, thank you for these people.
Bless them and keep them.
Make your face shine upon them and be gracious to them.
Turn your face towards all of us and give us your shalom.
Amen.
There should be volunteers at the prayer tent.
If you would like to talk to somebody,
pray with somebody other than that, go in peace.
We love you.